magazines.com 2019-04-04

# Privacy Policy | Magazines.com

#### General

At Magazines.com™, your privacy is important to us. We use the information you provide to us: (i) to process your order(s), (ii) to reply to your questions, (iii) to incorporate your feedback into improvements to our site, and (iv) to provide you with information about our other products and services. We also use your information in an effort to provide you with a superior customer experience, including using information to develop personalized shipping experiences and histories in order to customize products, promotions, emails, updates or special offers. We obtain your consent to use your information in this way when you place an order with us or through other communications with you. Except as described in this policy, we will not give, sell, or rent your personal information or specific account activity to any third party for any reason without your consent.

#### Information We Collect When You Visit Our Site

When you visit Magazines.com, we collect your IP address, browser type and domain name, and we log the length of time of your visit and the number of times you purchase from us. We assign you a unique customer number to help keep track of your future visits.

We do use tracking software to observe user traffic patterns throughout our site; but we do not correlate this information with data about individual users. Tracking information is used only to determine which areas of our site users like and don't like, and how well each page performs on behalf of our guests. This helps us continue to build a better service for you. We also monitor search terms and titles entered at our site as a means of knowing what interests our customers; however, we do not track which terms a particular user enters.

For visitors who make purchases on our site, please see the section below entitled “Information We Collect When You Place an Order”.

#### Use of Cookies on Our Site

Cookies are a mechanism to remember information about a visitor from one page to another. Web browsers store cookies so that the browser itself can remember certain information and then, on request, pass all that information up to the server at one time. We use cookies to remember your name and the contents of your shopping cart. This allows you to leave our site, come back later, and still have the contents of your shopping cart intact. It also lets us personalize your experience at magazines.com, tailoring the content to your interests. Our site requires the use of cookies. Turning off cookies or rejecting the Magazines.com cookie will prevent you from accessing the site.

We use AdWords remarketing to market our sites across the web. We place a cookie on a browser, and then a third party (Google) reads these cookies and may serve an ad on a third-party site. You may opt out of this ad serving on Google's opt out page. If you are concerned about third-party cookies served by networks, you should also visit the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.

We have implemented Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting to help market our site across the web. We place a cookie on a browser, and then a third party (Google) reads these cookies and may serve an ad on a third-party site. You may opt out of this ad serving on Google’s opt out page. We also use cookies to improve the performance of our advertising on other websites. To opt-out of our data collection for targeted advertising on other sites, click here to Opt Out Now.

If you are concerned about third-party cookies served by networks, you should also visit the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.

#### Information We Collect When You Place an Order

At Magazines.com we use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology to encrypt the information you send us when you place an online order. You will notice the padlock in the browser or that the http in the url becomes https when logged in, or on pages during the checkout process.

If you place an online order, our secure order form requests contact, billing, and payment (such as your credit card number) information. Contact information from the order form (email address, name, billing and shipping address and phone number) may be used to send order information about your order to you. Your contact information is also used to get in touch with you should we have questions regarding your order or should we need to notify you of the status of your order. Further, as a valued Magazines.com customer you may receive special offers, coupons, and exclusive promotions via email. If you prefer not to receive these emails from us you can easily manage your email preferences. In every promotional email we send, there is an unsubscribe or opt-out link at the bottom of the email. Click the link, and after your request is processed you will no longer receive promotional emails.

We use the information you provide about yourself when placing an order to complete the order. It is necessary to furnish this information to our third party fulfillment partners, such as magazine publishers, in order to quickly fulfill your order, as well as in connection with the processing of credit card payments. For email addresses specifically, Magazines.com does not share this information with other parties, except when a subscription contains a digital component.

Please note that even if you choose to not receive some marketing emails from us, you will still receive our transactional emails, such as messages relating to the status of your order, or information about your account.

The payment information we collect is used ONLY to bill you for products you purchase. For your convenience, your address information is stored on a secure server that allows you to reorder by entering your username and password. You may also place an autorenew order that will allow you to receive subscriptions on a regular basis without the need to reenter that order every time. If you choose autorenew, your credit card information is securely stored. You may cancel this order at any time prior to shipping by contacting us using the Contact Page or calling our toll free number 866-505-7501.

On some pages, you can submit information about other people. For example, if you order a gift online and want it sent directly to the recipient, you will need to submit the recipient’s address. In this circumstance, the types of personal information collected are name, address, email address, and phone number.

We also employ third parties to perform services or functions on our behalf in order to improve our site, to maintain our site and software, for merchandising, marketing and promotional efforts, and for communications or other services. During the purchase process, at the time of checkout we may share your information (other than email addresses) with such service providers or intermediaries to help identify offers for products and services from other parties that may be of interest to you. This information is not further provided to advertisers or other third parties without your consent, and in the event such service providers or intermediaries obtain any personal information during that process, it will not be used by them other than in the performance of their services for us. We may also employ third parties to analyze our sales data or to assist in marketing and personalizing product information.

We seek to ensure that contractors, service providers, and other third parties who work with us to support our business or otherwise make the Magazines.com site available (including the software, applications and services provided on our website) protect the personal information that they store, access or obtain in connection with our services, including, when possible, through contractual obligations to safeguard the confidentiality of such information and use it only for the purposes for which it is disclosed to, or accessed by, them. The information given to publishers is subject to the data protection and security practices of those individual publishers.

#### Disclosure of Information to Other Third Parties

It may be necessary, by law, legal process, litigation, and/or requests from governmental authorities for us to disclose certain of the information you have provided us to applicable third parties. We may also disclose this information if we determine that for purposes of law enforcement or other issues of public importance, disclosure is necessary or appropriate. We may also disclose this information if we determine that disclosure is reasonably necessary to enforce our terms of service or protect our operations or users. Additionally, we may share personal information with our subsidiaries and affiliated entities, primarily for business and operational purposes. We reserve the right to disclose and transfer all information related to Magazines.com, including personal information we collect to a subsequent owner, co-owner or operator of our website or one of our databases or in the event of a reorganization, merger, or sale of Magazines.com. We will not otherwise sell your information to third parties.

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and support the correct use of information, we have put in place physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard the information we collect online and that you otherwise provide to us. While we endeavor to protect the privacy of your account and other personal information we hold in our records, we cannot guarantee complete security. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors, may compromise the security of user information at any time.

#### Unsubscribe/Opt-Out

As noted above, if you decide to unsubscribe from/opt out of our newsletter or other communications from us, our emails provide you the opportunity to do so. You can also unsubscribe/opt-out by using the Contact Page with your email address and the word unsubscribe in the subject.

#### Access, Modify, or Delete Information/Deactivate

You can access all your personally identifiable information that we collect and maintain by contacting us through our toll-free number at 866-505-7501. We use this procedure to better safeguard your information. You may request additional information, including specific pieces of personal information collected and you can correct factual errors in your personally identifiable information by sending us a request to: Magazines.com, LLC, a RenewCo Company, 325 Seaboard Lane, #150, Franklin, Tennessee 37067. You may also use this contact information to request the deletion of personal information, and to inquire about sharing your information with third parties.

We keep your information for our internal use for as long as such information is relevant to us. If you wish to request that we remove your information on record with us or that you not receive future communications from us, you may do so by using the Contact Page with your request or by calling our toll free number at 1-800-624-2946.

To protect your privacy and security, we take reasonable steps to verify your identity before taking these actions with respect to you information in our records.

#### Visitors from Outside of the United States

Magazines.com is hosted in the United States. If you are visiting this service from outside the US, your information may be transferred to, stored and processed in the US in accordance with this policy and applicable US laws. Please note that data protection and other applicable laws of the United States may not be as comprehensive as those laws or regulations in your country or may otherwise differ from the data protection or consumer protection laws in your country. We do not currently ship to the EU. To the extent, however, that we collect personal information from EU customers who may visit our site, please specifically note the following applicable policies which are abided by in conjunction with measures described elsewhere in this policy:

  * We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose.
  * If we are relying on your consent to process your personal data, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. You may do so at any time by contacting us at service@magazines.com
  * You may request access to your personal data (commonly known as a data subject access request). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are properly processing it.
  * You may request that we transfer your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or the third party you have chosen, the data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to provide services to you.
  * If you are situated in the EU and have a question or concern regarding our privacy practices or procedures, please contact our Data Protection Officer at gdpr-officer@therenewco.com. You also have the right to address any concerns you have about our privacy practices at any time with your local Supervisory Authority

#### Children Under the Age of 13

We do not knowingly collect information about or from children under 13 without parental consent, nor do we or any of our third parties knowingly direct any solicitations or advertisements to children under 13. If we learn that a child under the age of 13 has submitted personal information online without parental consent, we will take reasonable measures to delete the information promptly and not use such information for any purpose, except where necessary to protect the safety of the child or others as required or allowed by law. If you believe a child under 13 has provided us with personal information, please contact us.

#### Questions or Comments

There is a special instructions box at checkout to add questions or comments about your order. We also offer a toll free number, 866-505-7501, to contact our Customer Service Department. Alternatively, you can use our Contact Page.

We read, and try to respond promptly to, each message that we receive from a customer. The information you send us is used to respond directly to your questions and comments. We may also keep your email correspondence on file so that we may better serve you should you have additional questions in the future. While it is highly unusual, should you experience an interaction to a particular supplement, we do encourage you to contact us so that we may advise the manufacturer.

#### Links

This site contains links to other sites. Magazines.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other sites.

#### Changes to Privacy Policy

Magazines.com reserves the right to modify or amend this privacy policy at any time. It is our practice to post any changes we make to our privacy policy on this page, and the date this policy was last revised is identified at the bottom of this page. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. You will be notified of any material changes to this privacy policy which are less protective of your information prior to such changes becoming effective. We may notify you of these changes by email reminders, by notice on this site, or by other acceptable means.

#### Contacting the Site

If you have any questions about this policy, our practices, or your dealings with this site, you can contact: Customer Service, Magazines.com, 325 Seaboard Lane, #150, Franklin, Tennessee 37067. Phone: 1-800-624-2946.

#### Your California Privacy Rights

Under California Civil Code Section 1798.83, California residents who provide us with personal information may be entitled to request and obtain from us one time per calendar year information about the customer information we shared, if any, with other businesses for their own direct marketing uses. To obtain this information from us, please send your request the mailing address found under the “How to Contact Us” link below and write “Your California Privacy Rights” in the subject field. Please include your return address and email address if you wish. We are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or do not have complete information.

#### Acceptance of Policy

Your use of our site constitutes your acceptance of our Terms of Service and Privacy Policy.

Revised Aug 2, 2018
